<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Kershia Mukoro Blog</title>
        <link>https://kershiamukoro.github.io/KershiaMukoro.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Kershia Mukoro Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A November to Remember: Lessons from the Ledge]]></title>
            <link>https://kershiamukoro.github.io/KershiaMukoro.github.io/blog/2024/01/31/2023-12-01-welcome/second-attempt</link>
            <guid>https://kershiamukoro.github.io/KershiaMukoro.github.io/blog/2024/01/31/2023-12-01-welcome/second-attempt</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Our latest attempt to conquer Pikes Peak on November 10, 2023, faced us with freezing temperatures and knee-deep snow, ultimately leading to an unsuccessful climb. The challenge became apparent when my friend suffered from severe altitude sickness, making him extremely fatigued. We were just 2 miles from the summit, well past the A-frame shelter, but the effort needed to wade through the snow and his worsening condition forced us to slow down considerably.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our latest attempt to conquer Pikes Peak on November 10, 2023, faced us with freezing temperatures and knee-deep snow, ultimately leading to an unsuccessful climb. The challenge became apparent when my friend suffered from severe altitude sickness, making him extremely fatigued. We were just 2 miles from the summit, well past the A-frame shelter, but the effort needed to wade through the snow and his worsening condition forced us to slow down considerably.</p>
<p>Our initial plan was to celebrate reaching the summit by taking the Cog Railway back down, a convenient option for hikers. Unlike my friend, altitude sickness never affects me, which put us in a difficult position when deciding our next steps. We had two choices:</p>
<p>The first option was to give my extra base layers to my friend, push to the summit myself, and then catch the train down, leaving him to possibly make it to the top on his own or call for rescue services. This would require me to drive up Pikes Peak Highway, a 2-3 hour journey in the snow, to pick him up. The thought of leaving him alone, especially underprepared in terms of clothing and facing potential hypothermia or frostbite, filled me with dread.</p>
<p>The second option, and the one we chose, was to turn back. This meant retracing our steps, resulting in a round-trip hike totaling over 20 miles, compared to the approximately 13 miles one-way trip if we could have made it to the summit and taken the Cog Railway back down. This decision highlighted a crucial mistake on my part. Used to feeling warm from physical exertion, I quickly became cold once we stopped moving. We halted not only for my friend's condition but also to allow me to use my cellphone to contact Search and Rescue to inform them of our predicament and to check on the status of Pikes Peak Highway—which turned out to be closed—we had no choice but to proceed on foot. Removing my gloves to use my phone meant my hands got cold very fast, and I struggled to get my gloves back on. I eventually ended up with frost nip on my thumb, a painful reminder of the importance of accessible warmth.</p>
<p>The journey back was taxing. I momentarily lost sight of my friend in the snow, anxiety set in with the realization that our descent was taking far longer than expected. However, the sight of Barr Camp's entrance was a beacon of relief. As we arrived at Barr Camp, we were greeted by the caretakers and five other hikers who were planning to stay overnight before embarking on their Pikes Peak summit attempt the next day. Our arrival happened to coincide with one of the hiker's birthdays. Enveloped in the cabin's warmth, sipping hot chamomile tea and hot chocolate, we shared laughter, sang Happy Birthday, and enjoyed a slice of birthday cake. This unexpected gathering of fellow adventurers added a sense of camaraderie and warmth to our otherwise chilly journey.</p>
<p>This ordeal taught us the vital lesson of being thoroughly prepared. My heavy pack, always stocked with food, tools, and extra battery packs, proved its worth. After an hour of warming up, we resumed our trek back to Barr Trail parking, navigating the snow with our phones and lights fully charged. Despite the challenges, we safely reached our car, a testament to our resilience and preparation.</p>
<p>Covering a distance of 21.31 miles in 12 hours and 7 minutes, this journey was a stark reminder of the unpredictable nature of mountain hiking and the critical importance of preparation, especially in adverse conditions.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="icy-insights-and-frozen-wisdom">Icy Insights and Frozen Wisdom<a href="https://kershiamukoro.github.io/KershiaMukoro.github.io/blog/2024/01/31/2023-12-01-welcome/second-attempt#icy-insights-and-frozen-wisdom" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Icy Insights and Frozen Wisdom" title="Direct link to Icy Insights and Frozen Wisdom">​</a></h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>The Unpredictability of Altitude Sickness:</strong> We realized that altitude sickness can strike even experienced hikers unexpectedly. Understanding its symptoms and being prepared to respond appropriately is essential.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Importance of Staying Together:</strong> The decision to stay together, even when facing a difficult situation, reinforced the importance of companionship and mutual support in the wilderness.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Value of Preparation:</strong> This hike underscored the significance of meticulous preparation, not just in terms of gear but also in understanding the route, potential challenges, and having a clear plan for emergencies.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Handling Cold Weather:</strong> The experience of getting cold and struggling to put my gloves back on taught us the importance of easy access to warm clothing and gloves during cold weather hikes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Kindness of Fellow Hikers:</strong> Meeting fellow hikers at Barr Camp and sharing a birthday celebration with them reminded us of the strong sense of community among outdoor enthusiasts. Their camaraderie and generosity provided much-needed warmth and encouragement.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Resilience and Determination:</strong> The decision to turn back and face a much longer hike in challenging conditions tested our resilience and determination. It reinforced our commitment to safety and making responsible choices.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Overall, our Pikes Peak adventure taught us that even in the face of adversity, preparation, companionship, and a positive mindset can make a significant difference in ensuring a safe and memorable outdoor experience.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pikes Peak Adventure: Lessons Learned from Running Out of Water]]></title>
            <link>https://kershiamukoro.github.io/KershiaMukoro.github.io/blog/2023/12/04/2023-12-01-welcome/first-attempt</link>
            <guid>https://kershiamukoro.github.io/KershiaMukoro.github.io/blog/2023/12/04/2023-12-01-welcome/first-attempt</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[On a sunny September 19, 2019, my boots hit the Barr Trail, eager for the ascent of Pikes Peak. With a backpack brimming with 4 liters of water, snacks, and essentials, I felt ready for anything. Yet, the mountain had its tests in store, starting with an unexpected blast of 79-degree heat that soon put our preparation to the test.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On a sunny September 19, 2019, my boots hit the Barr Trail, eager for the ascent of Pikes Peak. With a backpack brimming with 4 liters of water, snacks, and essentials, I felt ready for anything. Yet, the mountain had its tests in store, starting with an unexpected blast of 79-degree heat that soon put our preparation to the test.</p>
<p>The hike began under a clear blue sky at 08:56 AM. Right from the start, Pikes Peak offered a mix of welcoming and warning signs — a playful hint at the challenge ahead. Despite the conflicting mileage on the signs, we ventured into the heart of the trail, greeted by its infamous switchbacks. These early twists and turns, leading to the Incline Access point, were a true test of our resolve, especially after my encounters with other Colorado giants.</p>
<p>Leaving the Access point behind, the trail unveiled its wonders: arch-like rock formations and the serene No Name Creek. Yet, it was Lightning Point that truly took our breath away, offering a distant glimpse of our summit goal. However, the lure of the view couldn't keep us for long, with Barr Camp beckoning just a mile ahead.</p>
<p>It was at this juncture that my companion revealed his empty water bottle, a silent testament to the day's heat. Without hesitation, I shared my spare, a small act of camaraderie on this towering adventure. Barr Camp, though welcoming, reminded us of the wilderness's rules: no drinking water. Thankfully, my trusty life straw turned the mountain stream into a lifesaving oasis.</p>
<p>With replenished bottles, we pressed on, the trail winding northward and upward through more switchbacks, past the Bottomless Pit Trail junction, and finally breaking free from the tree line near the Timberline A-frame shelter. This rustic refuge, offering water from a nearby creek, was a welcome sight on our descent.</p>
<p>Beyond the shelter, the world transformed into an alpine wonderland, with the Roberts Memorial marking our progress. The Golden Stairs loomed ahead, a series of short switchbacks leading us tantalizingly close to our goal. With each step, the summit drew nearer, until at last, the vast expanse of the summit plateau unfolded before us.</p>
<p>Standing atop Pikes Peak, the journey's trials faded into the background, overshadowed by the sheer majesty of the views. After soaking in the scenery and capturing memories through our lenses, we began our descent, spirits high and water bottles full, courtesy of the Summit House.</p>
<p>Our adventure concluded just shy of 9 hours, a testament to the mountain's challenge and our determination. This journey was more than a hike; it underscored the beauty of nature, the critical role of being well-prepared, and the strength of camaraderie through challenging times.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="lessons-learned-from-our-pikes-peak-adventure">Lessons Learned from Our Pikes Peak Adventure<a href="https://kershiamukoro.github.io/KershiaMukoro.github.io/blog/2023/12/04/2023-12-01-welcome/first-attempt#lessons-learned-from-our-pikes-peak-adventure" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Lessons Learned from Our Pikes Peak Adventure" title="Direct link to Lessons Learned from Our Pikes Peak Adventure">​</a></h3>
<p>Our adventure up Pikes Peak taught us invaluable lessons that extend far beyond the trail. Here are the key takeaways from our journey:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Preparation is Key</strong>: Carrying enough water, snacks, and the right gear can make a significant difference in your hiking experience. Always anticipate the unexpected and plan accordingly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Value of Teamwork</strong>: Sharing resources and supporting each other in times of need not only strengthens bonds but can also be a lifesaver. The act of sharing a spare water bottle was a simple yet profound gesture of camaraderie.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Adaptability and Resilience</strong>: Facing the unpredictability of weather and physical challenges, we learned the importance of being adaptable and resilient. Knowing when to press on and when to turn back is crucial for mountain safety.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Lifesaving Simplicity of a Life Straw</strong>: This experience highlighted the importance of having a reliable method to purify water directly from natural sources, demonstrating that sometimes the simplest tools can be the most essential.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Personal Limits and Safety</strong>: Understanding and respecting our own limits and those of our companions is vital. Safety should always come first, even if it means altering your plans.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Joy of the Journey</strong>: Despite the challenges, the sense of accomplishment and the stunning beauty of Pikes Peak made every step worth it. The journey itself is as rewarding as reaching the destination.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>These lessons will accompany us on all future adventures, reminding us of the importance of preparation, teamwork, and respect for nature's unpredictability.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
            <link>https://kershiamukoro.github.io/KershiaMukoro.github.io/blog/blog</link>
            <guid>https://kershiamukoro.github.io/KershiaMukoro.github.io/blog/blog</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to my blog Wandering the Wilds!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="welcome-to-my-blog-wandering-the-wilds">Welcome to my blog Wandering the Wilds!<a href="https://kershiamukoro.github.io/KershiaMukoro.github.io/blog/blog#welcome-to-my-blog-wandering-the-wilds" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Welcome to my blog Wandering the Wilds!" title="Direct link to Welcome to my blog Wandering the Wilds!">​</a></h3>
<p>I'm Kershia, a tech enthusiast, a soldier in the Army Reserves, and a medical lab specialist. I have a passion for simplifying complex concepts and making them accessible to all. When I'm not immersed in technology or serving my country, I'm exploring the great outdoors with my three beloved dogs.</p>
<p><img align="center" src="https://kershiamukoro.github.io/KershiaMukoro.github.io/assets/images/collage-313a19cf9bd1b5dac1f33d6cc34f192b.png" alt="Hiking Photos" width="500" hspace="100"></p>
<p>Join me on this blog as I combine my diverse interests to provide you with engaging and informative content. We'll embark on  adventures with my canine companions, Holly, Tabitha, and Moji, and    explore the stunning landscapes of Colorado's mountains.</p>
<p>Whether you're an outdoor enthusiast or just looking for some tech insights, there's something here for everyone. Thank you for visiting, and I can't wait to share this journey with you!</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>